# Luiz Felipe Falcao



falcao.lfj@yahoo.com



linkedin.com/in/luizfelipejfalcao



(672) 513-2641



http://www.luizfelipefalcao.com

# Summary

Bachelor of Computer Science and passionate about Javascript and its frameworks like ReactJS, I am a front-end web developer with 3+ years of experience that always seeks professional development using this stack.

I currently develop personal projects, in addition to looking for a job opportunity in order to improve my skills and learn more about the world of web development.

My skills include creating Single Page Applications (SPA's) and Landing Pages developing the concepts of componentization nailed by ReactJS. I also use the Firebase database and authenticator for excellent real-time performance, as well as Material-UI and Styled-Components for the stylization of my project.

# **Experience**

# Front-end Web Developer

Utopia Tech PTY LTD

Oct 2020 - Jul 2021 (10 months)

I worked with this great team as a front-end web developer, implementing pages for the main website that the company is developing and whose business solutions are the final product.

I implemented pages, features, filter categories and components using the following tools:

- Javascript as programming language;
- ReactJS and NextJs as frameworks;
- CSS and SASS for stylization;
- Consumption of API's;
- Jira for management and workflow;
- Use of Git and Gitlab for version control of our applications;

Stack: Javascript, ReactJS, NextJS, HTML5, CSS, SASS, Git, Gitlab, VSCode.



# Software Engineer | Lua | IUP

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2018 - Apr 2020 (2 years 4 months)

As a software developer using the Lua programming language and its libraries such as IUP (Portable User Interface), I worked in the maintenance of the SJD (Didactic Games Simulator), optimizing the simulator's performance with new features, instances and new elements used in each simulation, thus improving simulation performance and student learning.

Stack: Lua, IUP, PostgreSQL, VS Code, Linux Server.



# **Brazilian Marine Corps - IT Support Technician**

#### Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2011 - Jan 2018 (7 years 1 month)

As a technician in support of computers and servers I worked maintaining and improving the computational and network services of the Battalion of Armored Marines.

As a combatant in this same battalion, I was a mechanic of the SK105A2S Kürassier tank and participated in the various exercises carried out in that battalion.



# **Brazilian Marine Corps**

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2008 - Jan 2011 (3 years 1 month)

When I joined the Marine Corps of the Brazilian Navy, I served in the Marine Group of Ladário and operated in the most diverse exercises performed by that group.

#### **Education**



### Centro Universitário UniCarioca

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2013 - 2018

### **Licenses & Certifications**

ReactJS do zero ao avançado na prática - React/Redux - 17,5 horas - Udemy UC-35bc6bc6-bfb9-48f9-a06a-d8fef70457b2/



Cambly Certificate of Accomplishment - 24 hours of English conversation practice with Cambly's native English teachers - Cambly Inc.

ff4cef1d

#### Skills

Javascript • React.js • SASS • Material-UI • Firebase • Git • GitHub • Scrum • Jira • **PostgreSQL** 

#### **Honors & Awards**



Amphibious Merit Medal - Brazilian Navy - Marines Corps

Medal of amphibious merit, honor for the services provided and missions accomplished.